,URL,Text,Extracted Entities,Summary
0,https://www.npr.org/2022/11/12/1136205315/musk-twitter-bankruptcy-how-likely,"Elon Musk says Twitter bankruptcy is possible, but is that likely?

Enlarge this image toggle caption Jeff Chiu/AP Jeff Chiu/AP

Before Elon Musk took over Twitter, it was hardly a gangbusters business. The company is only occasionally profitable. Its userbase and advertising revenue is puny compared to social media rivals like Facebook and TikTok.

Yet the possibility of a looming Twitter bankruptcy was not a fate anyone ever seriously discussed.

Now, however, under the chaotic leadership of Musk, the mercurial billionaire has reportedly told staff that bankruptcy could be nigh if Twitter does not start making more money.

How could this be the case, and what exactly has changed?

In taking the company private in his $44 billion purchase of Twitter, Musk cashed in some of his Tesla stock and also saddled the social platform with $13 billion in debt, which is a massive obligation for a company the size of Twitter.

For context, the debt equals about seven times the company's projected earnings for 2022.

It's essentially a huge credit card, and the annual payment is $1 billion.

And that's a problem for Twitter, considering that its cash flow last year to pay for things like debt payments was just $632 million.

So where's the rest of the money going to come from?

Why bankruptcy could be in Twitter's interest

""It's hypothetically possible that he could use more of his Tesla stock to bail out Twitter, or turn to his cadre of co-investors, who would probably have no trouble finding the money,"" said Andy Wu, assistant professor at Harvard's business school who has studied the Musk takeover.

But if Musk and his backers deem that Twitter is not worth sinking more money into, the eye-popping debt payment could help make the case that bankruptcy is the best way forward for the company, Wu said.

""The saying ,'if you owe the bank $100, that's your problem, but if you owe the bank $100 million, that's the bank's problem' might apply here,"" said Wu, explaining that the investors and other lenders could take over the company if Twitter went through a bankruptcy proceeding, with Musk still serving as its chief executive. ""Bankruptcy would also allow Musk to refinance the debt, which would make the company more financially stable.""

Since Musk closed the deal to buy Twitter, financial analysts have pointed out that he vastly overpaid. Musk's attempts to wriggle out of the deal shows that he had misgivings about the $44 billion price.

Investment firm Wedbush Securities said the deal represented ""one of the most overpaid tech acquisitions in history,"" pegging Twitter's fair value at closer to $25 billion.

Knowing this, pushing Twitter into bankruptcy could at least help Musk restructure the debt in a way that is more favorable to him.

Adding even more pressure on the company is the mayhem unfolding internally, with the departure of a slew of top executives, some of whom were responsible for things like the safety of the platform and complying with federal regulations.

The personnel turmoil, plus the fact that major advertisers like General Motors, Pfizer and United Airlines have paused advertising in the midst of the chaos has heaped additional stress onto the company. This despite Musk's assurances to companies that he would not let Twitter morph into a ""free-for-all hellscape."" About 90% of Twitter's revenue comes from advertising.

However rocky Musk's ownership continues to be, Harvard's Wu is skeptical Musk and his investors are ever going to let Twitter completely fold.

Even if there is a bankruptcy, Twitter itself would likely operate pretty much as normal, he said.

""In addition to potential financial returns, my sense is that Musk and his co-investors are ideologically driven, that they're really driven by values,"" Wu said.

Musk has described himself as a ""free speech absolutist,"" and he has often been critical of speech policing on platforms like Twitter that he says limits the marketplace of ideas.

Wu said it's his sense that Musk and his backers are ""willing to lose money for the sake of that fight.""

'Eight dollars is not cost-prohibitive for scammers'

Questions about Twitter's long-term financial viability are real. Musk has previously estimated that the company is losing $3 million a day.

Musk has gone to drastic lengths to make Twitter a cheaper place to run, like laying off half of the company's staff, or about 3,700 jobs.

But that did not change what Musk sees as a core problem at the company, which is that it has just one primary way of making money: online advertising.

It is an unfortunate reality for the company right now, considering it is a miserable time to be in the online advertising business. A substantial pullback in ad spending has convulsed the tech industry. Facebook owner Meta has laid off 11,000 people. Snap let go of 20% of its staff. Other ad-reliant tech companies like Spotify and Google's YouTube are feeling the squeeze.

So Musk's solution is revamping a service called Twitter Blue by charging $8 a month for the once-coveted blue check. This way, Musk has argued, being ""verified"" on Twitter is no longer reserved for the elite and more people using the service will be authenticated.

So far, the program's launch has had the exact opposite effect. A flurry of accounts impersonating star athletes like Lebron James, former President Trump and companies including Eli Lilly and Pepsi, put a spotlight on just how quickly the blue-check-for-sale option could be used to spread deception.

In an effort to tame the proliferation of impersonators, Twitter appears to have paused Twitter Blue. The service is no longer available for purchase, and on its website, Twitter notes that ""accounts created on or after November 9, 2022 will be unable to subscribe to Twitter Blue at this time.""

Twitter, which does not appear to have any communications staff in the wake of the mass layoff, did not respond to a request for comment.

At the moment, Twitter Blue is far from the money-making initiative Musk had hoped it would be. But to Rachel Tobac, who runs Social Proof Security, a firm focused on preventing the manipulation of social media sites, if Twitter Blue is revived, the money generated from the new service is the least important thing.

""Eight dollars is not cost-prohibitive for scammers,"" she said. ""It is essential that Twitter figures out this whole official or not issue.""

Imagine, Tobac said, if an emergency service account with a blue check was opened by an impersonator and began dispending harmful advice about, say, where to seek shelter during a natural disaster.

Tobac also fears disinformation agents paying $8 to sow confusion and discord in connection with an election — something fresh on her mind, as the country awaits the final outcome of a number of key midterm election races.

""Right now, we have people making jokes, impersonating the president, impersonating Nintendo and Elon Musk is laughing at those jokes because he thinks they're funny right now,"" she said. ""What's not going to be funny is someone impersonating an election official and meddling and causing interference within the election results.""","[('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jeff', 'PERSON'), ('Chiu', 'PERSON'), ('AP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jeff', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chiu', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('/', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('AP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Before', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Now', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('44', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Tesla', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('13', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seven', 'NUMBER'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('annual', 'SET'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('1', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('last', 'DATE'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('632', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tesla', 'PERSON'), ('Andy', 'PERSON'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('assistant', 'TITLE'), ('professor', 'TITLE'), ('Harvard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('100', 'MONEY'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('100', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('chief', 'TITLE'), ('executive', 'TITLE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('44', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Wedbush', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Securities', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('25', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('General', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Motors', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pfizer', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Airlines', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('90', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Harvard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wu', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Eight', 'MONEY'), ('dollars', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('previously', 'DATE'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('3', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('day', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('3,700', 'NUMBER'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('right', 'DATE'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('owner', 'TITLE'), ('Meta', 'PERSON'), ('11,000', 'NUMBER'), ('20', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Google', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('YouTube', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('8', 'MONEY'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('month', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lebron', 'PERSON'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Eli', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lilly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Pepsi', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('9', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'MISC'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rachel', 'PERSON'), ('Tobac', 'PERSON'), ('Social', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Proof', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Security', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Eight', 'MONEY'), ('dollars', 'MONEY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tobac', 'PERSON'), ('impersonator', 'TITLE'), ('natural', 'CAUSE_OF_DEATH'), ('disaster', 'CAUSE_OF_DEATH'), ('Tobac', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('8', 'MONEY'), ('Right', 'DATE'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('Nintendo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'LOCATION'), ('Musk', 'LOCATION'), ('right', 'DATE'), ('now', 'DATE')]","– Elon Musk says he's open to bailing out Twitter if the social media company doesn't start making more money, and he's apparently got plenty of cash on hand to do just that. The problem is that Twitter is saddled with $13 billion in debt—seven times the company's projected earnings for 2022—and only has $632 million in cash on hand last year, NPR reports. ""It's hypothetically possible that he could use more of his Tesla stock to bail out Twitter, or turn to his cadre of co-investors, who would probably have no trouble finding the money,"" says Andy Wu, an assistant professor at Harvard's business school. ""The saying,'If you owe the bank $100, that's your problem, but if you owe the bank $100 million, that's the bank's problem' might apply here."" If Twitter does file for bankruptcy, it could help Musk by allowing him to refinance the debt, which would make the company ""more financially stable,"" says Wu. But even if Twitter does file for bankruptcy, it would likely operate as normal, says Wu. ""In addition to potential financial returns, my sense is that Musk and his co-investors are ideologically driven, that they"
1,https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/11/elon-musk-cautions-twitter-could-go-bankrupt,"Elon Musk warned that filing for bankruptcy was a distinct possibility for his newly acquired company, after he laid off half of the staff, which numbered 7,500 earlier this year, and made changes to the platform that are causing users, brands, and advertisers to fly the coop.

“Sorry that this is my first email to the whole company, but there is no way to sugarcoat the message,” Musk wrote to employees. “Without significant subscription revenue, there is a good chance Twitter will not survive the upcoming economic downturn.”

Musk sold nearly $4 billion worth of Telsa stock since reaching his deal to buy Twitter for $44 billion last month. He told Twitter employees on Thursday that he was selling his other company’s stock in order to “save Twitter.”

On top of mass layoffs and unwelcome platform changes, Musk told employees on Wednesday in an email that he is requiring them to come into the office for a minimum of 40 hours per week, ending the company’s work-from-home policy; he added that he had to personally approve any remote work requests.

Musk also said in the email, “We need roughly half of our revenue to be subscription,” alluding to the new controversial blue checkmark subscription service. The blue checkmark, which used to indicate a user’s verified identity to combat misinformation and scam accounts, now costs $8 per month and can be given to anyone who will pay. It’s unclear whether eventually users will have to show identity verification for a blue checkmark.

In the email, Musk mentioned the growing bot problem: “Over the next few days, the absolute top priority is finding and suspending any verified bots/trolls/spam.”

He echoed this on Twitter: “Going forward, accounts engaged in parody must include ‘parody’ in their name, not just in bio.”

Twitter content This content can also be viewed on the site it originates from.

Ironically, it was difficult to even find this tweet from the real Elon Musk’s Twitter account. One must sift through a sea of fake Elon Musks to find the real one, as a number of users are demonstrating the dangerousness of the new blue checkmark’s leniency, pairing his name with a paid-for checkmark.

CNN pointed out that under the new blue checkmark system, Twitter gave Jesus Christ verified status.","[('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('7,500', 'NUMBER'), ('earlier', 'DATE'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('4', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('Telsa', 'LOCATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('44', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('last', 'DATE'), ('month', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('40', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('week', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('8', 'MONEY'), ('month', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DURATION'), ('next', 'DURATION'), ('few', 'DURATION'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('’s', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('One', 'NUMBER'), ('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musks', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('CNN', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Christ', 'PERSON')]","– Elon Musk sent an email to Twitter employees this week, and it was a bleak one. ""Sorry that this is my first email to the whole company, but there is no way to sugarcoat the message,"" he wrote. ""Without significant subscription revenue, there is a good chance Twitter will not survive the upcoming economic downturn."" He added that he was selling his other company's stock in order to ""save Twitter,"" CNBC reports. Musk laid off half of the staff when he bought the company for $44 billion last month, and he told employees this week that they are now required to come into the office for a minimum of 40 hours per week, ending the company's work-from-home policy. ""We need roughly half of our revenue to be subscription,"" he wrote, referring to the company's controversial blue checkmark subscription service. ""Over the next few days, the absolute top priority is finding and suspending any verified bots/trolls/spam,"" he wrote. ""Going forward, accounts engaged in parody must include 'parody' in their name, not just in bio."" He also noted that going forward, ""accounts engaged in parody must include 'parody' in their name, not just in bio."""
2,https://www.msn.com/en-us/lifestyle/family/twitter-begins-a-new-wave-of-firings-by-letting-go-of-contractors-with-no-notice-reports-say/ar-AA143uF8,"© Provided by Business Insider Elon Musk is reportedly planning to slash roughly half of Twitter's 7,500 employees this week. But the conflict between Twitter's old guard and the new owner's loyalists is just getting started. NurPhoto/Getty Images

Twitter began firing contractors on Saturday, according to reports.

Some contractors told Axios they found out after being locked out of work accounts.

Contractors also shared fears that they would not be able to receive their final paychecks.

Twitter has began to lay off its contract workforce, with some contractors finding out through a loss of access to work accounts, according to reports.

Starting on Nov. 4, Twitter — under the new ownership of Tesla CEO Elon Musk — slashed its full-time employee workforce by nearly 50%.

Now, contractors appear to be the next target, with contractors telling Axios they were locked out of work accounts on Saturday. Similarly, many of Twitter's full-time employees also found out that they were being let go when they lost access to work platforms like Slack and email.

Some of these contractors work in content moderation, which had already been hit with layoffs, sources told Axios.

According to journalist Casey Newton, other departments, such as real estate and marketing, were also affected by contractor layoffs.

Some contractors told Axios they were worried about whether or not they would be able to receive their final paycheck, as many ended up on teams with no full-time employees following the layoffs.

Melissa Ingle, a content moderation contractor, told Axios that she was worried about how the layoffs would affect her and her family financially.

""This is no way to treat people,"" Ingle told Axios.

Following Musk's acquisition of Twitter, the company staff has been thrown into weeks of chaos.

Some laid-off Twitter staff were asked to come back after the company realized that they were essential to operations. Other Twitter staff filed a lawsuit, saying they were not given enough advance notice before their firings.

Now, employees are being asked by Musk to return to the office 40 hours a week or resign.

One current Twitter employee described the current environment as ""ruthless"" in an as-told-to essay by Insider's Jyoti Mann.

Twitter and representatives for Musk did not immediately respond to Insider's request for comment.","[('Business', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insider', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('7,500', 'NUMBER'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('week', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('guard', 'TITLE'), ('owner', 'TITLE'), ('Getty', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Images', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('Nov.', 'DATE'), ('4', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tesla', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CEO', 'TITLE'), ('50', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Now', 'DATE'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('journalist', 'TITLE'), ('Casey', 'PERSON'), ('Newton', 'PERSON'), ('contractor', 'TITLE'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('Melissa', 'PERSON'), ('Ingle', 'PERSON'), ('contractor', 'TITLE'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('Ingle', 'PERSON'), ('Axios', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Now', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('40', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('week', 'DURATION'), ('One', 'NUMBER'), ('current', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('current', 'DATE'), ('Jyoti', 'PERSON'), ('Mann', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON')]","– Elon Musk's mass layoffs at Twitter are now hitting contractors as well as full-time employees, Axios reports. On Saturday, some contractors found out they'd been fired when they were locked out of their work accounts. Similarly, many of Twitter's full-time employees found out the same when they lost access to work platforms like Slack and email. Some contractors work in content moderation, which had already been hit with layoffs. According to journalist Casey Newton, other departments, such as real estate and marketing, were also affected by contractor layoffs. Some contractors told Axios they were worried about whether or not they would be able to receive their final paycheck. Melissa Ingle, a content moderation contractor, told Axios that she was worried about how the layoffs would affect her and her family financially. ""This is no way to treat people,"" Ingle told Axios. Twitter and representatives for Musk did not immediately respond to Insider's request for comment. On Nov. 4, Twitter—under the new ownership of Musk—cut its full-time employee workforce by nearly 50%. Now, Musk is reportedly planning to slash roughly half of Twitter's 7,500 employees this week. But the conflict between Twitter's old guard and the new owner's loyalists"
3,https://www.politico.com/news/2022/11/12/dems-answers-musks-twitter-00066614,"Noting that the company is already under a 2011 consent decree with the Federal Trade Commission for previous security and privacy violations, Schakowksky said that “Musk should be held personally liable because he purchased Twitter, took it private, and made the conscious decision to violate the 2011 consent decree in which Twitter pledged, unequivocally, to protect consumer data.”

Earlier this week, a Twitter attorney said that Musk’s breakneck pace for setting up new systems, including the new subscription service, would lead to “major incidents.” The FTC responded with a highly unusual warning that they are watching the company with “deep concern.”

Musk’s lawyer reportedly tried to quell concerns from Twitter employees after the FTC’s warning.

“Twitter is already on privacy probation,” said Sen. Ed Markey (D-Mass.), who’s demanding answers from Musk about the wave of fake “verified” accounts — including one impersonating Markey himself.

“Every day at that company brings increasing chaos that threatens users’ wellbeing,” Markey added. “The FTC has an obligation to make sure Twitter and its leadership are abiding by their responsibilities under the law and agreements with regulators.”

Twitter did not respond to a request for comment. The vast majority of the company’s communications staff were laid off just over a week ago.

It’s not just data privacy that’s drawing Democratic scrutiny. Sen. Chris Murphy (D-Conn.) wants a powerful government council to investigate Saudi Arabia’s involvement in the Twitter deal. And President Joe Biden said the platform “spews lies,” adding a few days later that he too would like to see Musk’s foreign ties investigated.

Musk likely did himself no favors on the left when he endorsed Republicans the day before the midterm elections, arguing that a divided government is what’s best for the country. It was an unusual move for a tech mogul, given that his fellow billionaires tend to avoid stepping so directly into partisan politics.

And Musk tweeted out a false story about House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband just days after he took over the platform, stoking fears among advertisers and users that his promise of a more free and open dialogue on the platform would instead usher in a new era of misinformation and malicious content.

Musk also said recently that “it’s true that I’ve been under unfair & misleading attack for some time by leading Democrats,” and he’s exchanged Twitter barbs with leading Democrats like Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-N.Y.), who has over 13 million followers on the platform. Musk himself has over 110 million followers.

It’s the kind of behavior that will likely only increase friction with Democrats in the coming months.","[('2011', 'DATE'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trade', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Schakowksky', 'PERSON'), ('2011', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Earlier', 'DATE'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('week', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('FTC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('lawyer', 'TITLE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('FTC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ed', 'PERSON'), ('Markey', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Markey', 'PERSON'), ('Every', 'SET'), ('day', 'SET'), ('Markey', 'PERSON'), ('FTC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('a', 'DATE'), ('week', 'DATE'), ('ago', 'DATE'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Chris', 'PERSON'), ('Murphy', 'PERSON'), ('Saudi', 'COUNTRY'), ('Arabia', 'COUNTRY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('a', 'DATE'), ('few', 'DATE'), ('days', 'DATE'), ('later', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('day', 'DATE'), ('before', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('House', 'TITLE'), ('Speaker', 'TITLE'), ('Nancy', 'PERSON'), ('Pelosi', 'PERSON'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('recently', 'DATE'), ('attack', 'CAUSE_OF_DEATH'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Rep.', 'TITLE'), ('Alexandria', 'PERSON'), ('Ocasio', 'PERSON'), ('-', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('13', 'NUMBER'), ('million', 'NUMBER'), ('110', 'NUMBER'), ('million', 'NUMBER'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('coming', 'DATE'), ('months', 'DATE')]","– It's been a rough couple of days for Twitter CEO Elon Musk. First, the Federal Trade Commission warned that his breakneck pace for setting up new systems, including a new subscription service, would lead to ""major incidents."" Then, the company laid off most of its communications staff last week. Now, a former Twitter lawyer says Musk should be held ""personally liable"" because he bought Twitter, took it private, and ""made the conscious decision to violate the 2011 consent decree in which Twitter pledged, unequivocally, to protect consumer data,"" CNBC reports. The FTC is already on privacy probation for previous security and privacy violations at the company. ""Musk should be held personally liable because he purchased Twitter, took it private, and made the conscious decision to violate the 2011 consent decree in which Twitter pledged, unequivocally, to protect consumer data,"" former Twitter lawyer Jesse Schakowksky says. Schakowksky says Twitter violated that consent decree by allowing third-party apps to gain access to user data. He says the company also violated that consent decree by allowing third-party apps to gain access to user data. Twitter hasn't responded to Schakowksky's request for comment."
4,https://www.vox.com/recode/2022/11/12/23452396/elon-musk-twitter-jason-calacanis-david-sacks-alex-spiro-jared-birchall-inner-circle-war-room,"What you need to know about Elon’s inner circle at Twitter

Share All sharing options for: What you need to know about Elon’s inner circle at Twitter

Uncovering and explaining how our digital world is changing — and changing us.

As Elon Musk carries out his chaotic early days as Twitter’s new CEO — slashing staff, trolling employees and users alike, and freaking out advertisers — you might wonder, who is this guy getting his advice from?

In his first two weeks running Twitter, Musk has assembled a tight-knit group of his “war-room” advisers. Many members of the group are longtime confidants of Musk, and some of them have very little background in social media. Since Musk is the ultimate decision-maker, it’s unclear exactly how much power they hold at Twitter, but these figures have gained overnight influence over one of the world’s most powerful platforms for online communication.

To better understand how Musk plans on changing Twitter, it’s worth learning more about the backgrounds, relationships, and beliefs of the key men (none of Musk’s key advisers are women) who have Musk’s ear. None of Musk’s advisers responded to Recode’s request for comment.

Jason Calacanis

What he’s known for

Calacanis is an early-stage tech investor who has invested in Uber and Robinhood. He’s a popular media figure in tech who co-hosts two podcasts, This Week in Startups and All-In. He’s also a prolific tweeter and known for being a self-made master networker since his time as an early tech reporter in New York during the dot-com boom.

How he knows Musk

Musk and Calacanis have a friendship going back to Calacanis’s days starting the tech trade rag, Silicon Alley Reporter. Musk later invested in Calacanis’s now-defunct Google search competitor, Mahalo. And Calacanis was reportedly the first owner of Tesla’s Model S car.

We know that Calacanis has professed his loyalty to Musk as a friend from private texts released in court documents from the Twitter v. Elon Musk case.

In April, when Musk asked if Calacanis wanted to be an adviser for Twitter after the deal was done, he replied:

“Board member, advisor, whatever... you have my sword.”

What we know about his ideas for Twitter

Calacanis pitched Musk on charging users for verification check marks several months ago, a controversial idea that Musk has now put in place. “[W]hy should blue check marks be limited to the elite, press and celebrities? How is that democratic?” Calacanis wrote in a text to Musk in April.

Other ideas Calacanis pitched in texts to Musk include charging users for messaging a large group of users at one time, moving Twitter’s headquarters from San Francisco to Tesla’s extra factory space in Austin, splitting revenue with popular creators to post content on Twitter, and requiring employees to come to the office two times a week.

On the topic of content moderation, Calacanis has said in court-revealed texts to Musk that he wants to make Twitter’s algorithm and moderation more “understandable and fair.”

Political affiliation

Calacanis has been supportive of some Democratic party leaders such as Hillary Clinton in the past. He also fundraised money for a journalist to investigate progressive San Francisco District Attorney Chesa Boudin — whose opponents said he was too lax on crime — ahead of his June 2022 recall.

Relevant experience

Calacanis has a long history in media as an entrepreneur and journalist. After Silicon Alley Reporter, Calacanis started an early blogging company called Weblogs that sold to AOL for $25 million in 2005.

David Sacks

What he’s known for

Sacks is a tech investor and entrepreneur. He was the founding chief operating officer of PayPal, the founder and CEO of Yammer (a work messaging and social media app that sold to Microsoft in 2012 for $1.2 billion), and the interim CEO of Zenefits in 2016.

Sacks, like Calacanis, co-hosts the popular All-In podcast and is a well-known figure in the tech industry.

How he knows Musk

Sacks and Musk go way back to their days as members of what’s been dubbed the “PayPal Mafia” — a group of early PayPal executives and employees, including billionaire tech entrepreneur and major Republican party donor Peter Thiel, who went on to found or invest in other successful tech companies.

What we know about his ideas for Twitter

Sacks has tweeted that contrary to media reports, he has no formal role at Twitter and is simply helping out as needed. Sacks has been weighing in on important decisions, though, as he reportedly was discussing making Twitter users pay a monthly fee to use the service after a period of time, according to Platformer.

The tech investor has also vocally defended Musk’s elimination of free blue check mark verification for public figures, and he has criticized “the entitled elite” for complaining about the matter.

Political affiliation

Sacks, who has donated to Democratic and Republican campaigns in the past, is increasingly becoming a popular figure in conservative media Twitter circles. A recent article in the New Republic profiling Sacks called him “the leading practitioner of a new right-wing sensibility that has emerged in the political realignments provoked by Trumpism and the pandemic.” Like Calacanis, Sacks was a leading supporter of the recall Boudin campaign.

Sacks is aligned with Musk in supporting negotiations with Russia to end the war in Ukraine, and has also criticized social media platforms for putting permanent bans on politicians.

Experience in social media management

Sacks co-founded a social podcasting platform called Callin — similar to Clubhouse, but one that lets you keep and edit your recordings — that launched last September. He also co-founded Yammer, an enterprise social media app, in 2008.

Sriram Krishnan

What he’s known for

Krishnan is an investor at top tech venture capitalist firm Andreessen Horowitz and previously held leadership positions at major social media companies like Facebook, Snap, and Twitter.

He’s also known for hosting the popular tech interview program, the Good Time Show, that he hosts with his wife Aarthi Ramamurthy.

How he knows Musk

Krishnan and Musk reportedly intersected in Silicon Valley circles a few years back, but their most notable collaboration was last year when Musk made an impromptu live appearance on Krishnan’s interview show on Clubhouse.

What we know about his ideas for Twitter

Krishnan declined to comment to the BBC about “anything Twitter related” earlier this month.

Political affiliation

Unknown.

Experience in social media management

Sriram Krishnan is the only one of Elon Musk’s inner circle of Twitter advisers who has actually worked at the company and for other major social media platforms.

Krishnan built his career as a social media exec, first working at Facebook (now Meta) on mobile monetization from 2013 to 2016, and then at Snap, and later Twitter from 2017 to 2019 working on its core product, before becoming a crypto investor at Andreessen Horowitz.

Alex Spiro

What he’s known for

Spiro is a top celebrity lawyer who represents Musk. In the past, he has repped A-list clients such as Jay-Z, Chance the Rapper, and tennis champion Naomi Osaka.

How he knows Musk

Spiro isn’t just Musk’s lawyer, but one of his “closest lieutenants, confidants, and consiglieres,” according to a profile by the Washington Post. He has represented Musk on high-profile cases from a defamation lawsuit he faced in 2018 to his dispute about buying Twitter.

What we know about his ideas for Twitter

Spiro advises on legal policy at Twitter but hasn’t shared his ideas for how to change the company.

Political affiliation

Spiro keeps a private profile so we don’t know much about his politics, but the Post reported that he served as an adviser to the criminal justice reform organization the United Justice Coalition.

Experience in social media management

None.

Jared Birchall

What he’s known for

Birchall is mainly known for being Musk’s “straight-laced” family wealth manager. He is also the CEO of Neuralink, a neurotechnology company co-founded by Musk.

How he knows Musk

Like Musk’s attorney Spiro, Birchall is especially close with Musk. Bloomberg called him the billionaire’s “right-hand deputy.”

Birchall met Musk a decade ago when he was working at Morgan Stanley in Los Angeles, according to the Wall Street Journal. He reportedly impressed Musk by gathering hundreds of millions of dollars in loans at a time when Musk was “strapped for cash.”

The wealth adviser also reportedly hired an investigator to dig up dirt on the British cave diver who criticized Musk for trying to get involved in the rescue of a trapped soccer team in Thailand in 2018.

What we know about his ideas for Twitter

It’s unclear what specific ideas Birchall has for Twitter, but we do know he was critical in managing relations with bankers such as Morgan Stanley — which led financing of the Twitter deal, according to texts revealed in court documents.

Political affiliation

Unknown.

Experience in social media management

None.","[('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Uncovering', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('early', 'DURATION'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('CEO', 'TITLE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('overnight', 'TIME'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Jason', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Uber', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('two', 'NUMBER'), ('This', 'DATE'), ('Week', 'DATE'), ('All', 'MISC'), ('-', 'MISC'), ('In', 'MISC'), ('reporter', 'TITLE'), ('New', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('York', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('Silicon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Reporter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Google', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mahalo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('owner', 'TITLE'), ('Tesla', 'PERSON'), ('Model', 'TITLE'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('several', 'DATE'), ('months', 'DATE'), ('ago', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('San', 'CITY'), ('Francisco', 'CITY'), ('Tesla', 'PERSON'), ('Austin', 'CITY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('two', 'NUMBER'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('week', 'DURATION'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('party', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Hillary', 'PERSON'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('past', 'DATE'), ('journalist', 'TITLE'), ('progressive', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('San', 'CITY'), ('Francisco', 'CITY'), ('District', 'TITLE'), ('Attorney', 'TITLE'), ('Chesa', 'PERSON'), ('Boudin', 'PERSON'), ('June', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('entrepreneur', 'TITLE'), ('journalist', 'TITLE'), ('Silicon', 'MISC'), ('Alley', 'MISC'), ('Reporter', 'TITLE'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('AOL', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('25', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('2005', 'DATE'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Sacks', 'PERSON'), ('entrepreneur', 'TITLE'), ('chief', 'TITLE'), ('operating', 'TITLE'), ('officer', 'TITLE'), ('PayPal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('founder', 'TITLE'), ('CEO', 'TITLE'), ('Microsoft', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('2012', 'DATE'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('1.2', 'MONEY'), ('billion', 'MONEY'), ('CEO', 'TITLE'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('All', 'MISC'), ('-', 'MISC'), ('In', 'MISC'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Sacks', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('PayPal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('entrepreneur', 'TITLE'), ('Republican', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('party', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Thiel', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sacks', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('monthly', 'SET'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('past', 'DATE'), ('conservative', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('right', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('-', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('wing', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Trumpism', 'PERSON'), ('Calacanis', 'PERSON'), ('Sacks', 'PERSON'), ('Boudin', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Russia', 'COUNTRY'), ('war', 'CAUSE_OF_DEATH'), ('Ukraine', 'COUNTRY'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('last', 'DATE'), ('September', 'DATE'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('Sriram', 'PERSON'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('Andreessen', 'PERSON'), ('Horowitz', 'PERSON'), ('previously', 'DATE'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Good', 'MISC'), ('Time', 'MISC'), ('Show', 'MISC'), ('Aarthi', 'PERSON'), ('Ramamurthy', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Silicon', 'LOCATION'), ('Valley', 'CITY'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('few', 'DURATION'), ('years', 'DURATION'), ('last', 'DATE'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Krishnan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('BBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'MISC'), ('earlier', 'DATE'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('month', 'DATE'), ('Sriram', 'PERSON'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Krishnan', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Facebook', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('mobile', 'TITLE'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('to', 'DATE'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('2017', 'DATE'), ('to', 'DATE'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('Andreessen', 'PERSON'), ('Horowitz', 'PERSON'), ('Alex', 'PERSON'), ('Spiro', 'PERSON'), ('Spiro', 'PERSON'), ('lawyer', 'TITLE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('past', 'DATE'), ('A-list', 'MISC'), ('Rapper', 'TITLE'), ('Naomi', 'PERSON'), ('Osaka', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Spiro', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('lawyer', 'TITLE'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Washington', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Spiro', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Spiro', 'PERSON'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('United', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Justice', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Coalition', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jared', 'PERSON'), ('Birchall', 'PERSON'), ('Birchall', 'PERSON'), ('manager', 'TITLE'), ('CEO', 'TITLE'), ('Neuralink', 'LOCATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Like', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('Spiro', 'PERSON'), ('Birchall', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Bloomberg', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('deputy', 'TITLE'), ('Birchall', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('a', 'DATE'), ('decade', 'DATE'), ('ago', 'DATE'), ('Morgan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Stanley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Los', 'CITY'), ('Angeles', 'CITY'), ('Wall', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Street', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Journal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('millions', 'MONEY'), ('of', 'MONEY'), ('dollars', 'MONEY'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('investigator', 'TITLE'), ('British', 'NATIONALITY'), ('diver', 'TITLE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Thailand', 'COUNTRY'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Birchall', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'MISC'), ('Morgan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Stanley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION')]","– It's been less than two weeks since Elon Musk took over as CEO of Twitter, and he's already been criticized for his handling of the company. Now, a new report from Recode reveals that Musk has assembled a ""tight-knit group of his 'war-room' advisers,"" many of whom have known Musk for years and have ""very little background in social media."" The inner circle includes Jason Calacanis, who started Silicon Alley and was once Musk's first owner of Tesla's Model S car; David Sacks, who was the founding chief operating officer of PayPal and was once the interim CEO of Zenefits; Farhad Manjoo, a New York Times reporter who has written extensively about the tech industry; and Nick Karavites, an early investor and Twitter co-founder. Musk's advisers ""have gained overnight influence over one of the world's most powerful platforms for online communication,"" the report states, though it adds that it's ""unclear exactly how much power they hold at Twitter, but these figures have gained overnight influence over one of the world's most powerful platforms for online communication."""
5,https://news.yahoo.com/waiting-2-weeks-address-twitter-110801142.html?guccounter=1&guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9hcGkuZ2RlbHRwcm9qZWN0Lm9yZy8&guce_referrer_sig=AQAAANzLNVzWaIFvpMpBKIYllRx9I_peg90-RHcOeBg20QHqtoj1wYpiTO27C0ZajBaXrPi1CD1WoiBG_mIxn1ZqXDK2Pr0M8h8vNR3HFEM9UFhuI_gD8KWeRlS55s8U7H3PXKxBHs_RFTqVVd-B36YpPzanXhpGpqyTJPHjV5oN-QPl,"FilmMagic for HBO via Getty Images

Elon Musk told Twitter staff he's usually ""pretty responsive on email"" and replies ""within hours.""

The tech mogul waited two weeks after buying Twitter to send an all-staff email and host a company-wide Q&A.

Musk has ordered staff to return to the office or be fired, saying ""communication is much better.""

Two weeks after taking ownership of Twitter, tech mogul Elon Musk finally addressed the company's staff in a Q&A on Thursday. This came just hours after he sent his first ever company-wide email to Twitter workers, telling them to come back to the office for at least 40 hours a week.

During the Q&A, a transcript of which was published by The Verge, Musk told staff that he's actually usually ""pretty responsive on email."" This is despite Twitter workers complaining about his lack of communication in the 14 days since his takeover.

""I'm pretty responsive on email,"" Musk said, per The Verge. ""Every now and again, it's a crisis, and if I didn't respond within 24 hours, email me again. It rarely takes me longer than 24 hours to respond. Usually it's within hours.""

Before the email, sent in the early hours of Thursday morning, Twitter staff had only received generic emails sent by the company without Musk's name attached. Some workers spoke to WIRED earlier this week about the ""radio silence"" they had received from Musk and his advisors.

Yet Musk emphasized the importance of communication at Thursday's Q&A, telling staff that that was the reason why they could lose their job if they refused to return to the office without a valid exemption. ""It's just my philosophy that people are way more productive when they're in person because the communication is much better.""

Despite not communicating directly with most staff other than senior employees, Musk has posted dozens of tweets since taking ownership of the platform, with many announcements about planned changes. He tweeted on Wednesday that Twitter would ""do lots of dumb things in coming months.""

Story continues

Twitter has been pushing workers to rapidly develop some new features requested by Musk, such as changes to Twitter Blue. In the space of just two weeks, Musk has told engineers to get to work on a Vine reboot, announced a $7.99 monthly fee for users who want blue check marks after their names, and suspended some accounts after they impersonated him as a joke. He's also fired some of the company's top execs and laid off large numbers of staff as part of a plan to roughly halve Twitter's headcount.

""I'm a big believer in having just a maniacal sense of urgency,"" Musk said at the Twitter Q&A on Thursday after asking staff to try coax YouTubers onto Twitter. ""Just go 'aahh.' Hardcore.""

Musk also spoke about the company's high attrition rate and told staff that ""bankruptcy isn't out of the question.""

Read the original article on Business Insider","[('HBO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Getty', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Images', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('two', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('host', 'TITLE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Two', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elon', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('at', 'DURATION'), ('least', 'DURATION'), ('40', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('week', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('the', 'DURATION'), ('14', 'DURATION'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('24', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('24', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('early', 'DATE'), ('hours', 'DATE'), ('of', 'DATE'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('morning', 'TIME'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('earlier', 'DATE'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('week', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('Musk', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('months', 'DURATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Blue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('two', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('7.99', 'MONEY'), ('monthly', 'SET'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Q&A', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION')]","– Elon Musk sent his first-ever company-wide email to Twitter workers early Thursday, ordering them to come back to the office for at least 40 hours a week. Hours later, he held a company-wide Q&A, Business Insider reports. ""I'm pretty responsive on email,"" Musk said during the Q&A. ""Every now and again, it's a crisis, and if I didn't respond within 24 hours, email me again. It rarely takes me longer than 24 hours to respond. Usually it's within hours."" Musk said that communication was the reason why workers could lose their jobs if they refused to return to the office. ""It's just my philosophy that people are way more productive when they're in person because the communication is much better."" Before the email was sent, Twitter workers had only received generic emails sent by the company without Musk's name attached."
6,https://www.newsweek.com/tesla-twitter-impersonator-shares-aim-spoof-amid-blue-tick-horror-show-1759147,FAILED,[],"– The man who created a parody Twitter account that poked fun of Elon Musk and his Tesla company says he did so to show how ""incompetent"" Musk is. ""As I'm sure most creators of other fake verified accounts would agree, the goal of my fake Tesla account was to highlight how much of a thin-skinned, incompetent buffoon Elon is, but also I just wanted to make people laugh,"" Los Angeles musician Connor Musarra tells Newsweek. Musarra\'s account was one of a number of parody accounts that appeared on Twitter this week to expose flaws in Musk's Twitter Blue plan, which requires users to pay $8 for a verified account. ""If your product allows me, a random musician from LA to impersonate a billion-dollar company like Tesla just by spending $8, I would say that product is not well thought out,"" Musarra tells Newsweek. ""The Twitter Blue verification program is legitimately the dumbest addition to Twitter that I have seen in my entire time on there,"" he says. ""A man worth hundreds of billions, tens of billions for a product worth a couple billion, now begging users to pay $8 for a service that has been free since its inception. The $8 verification badge immediately introduced a level of misinformation that I don't"
7,https://redstate.com/jeffc/2022/11/12/leftists-are-trying-to-get-people-to-leave-twitter-its-not-going-to-work-n658116,"Folks on the left are still freaking out about Elon Musk buying Twitter. Ever since he bought the social media company, they have been screaming like drunken banshees about the prospect of people they don’t like being on equal footing when it comes to disseminating ideas and opinions.

It did not take them long after Musk took over to start brainstorming ways to ensure progressive supremacy over the platform. Indeed, these people are truly desperate.

The Washington Post tried to attack the company’s advertising revenue stream. Others have used the typical race-baiting strategy to persuade users that white nationalists were going to dominate the site.

None of these tactics have worked so far. But that doesn’t mean they aren’t still trying. Now, they are trying to convince people to abandon the platform and look for other social media sites to populate.

NBC News is keeping a running tally of celebrities who have vowed to leave the platform. These include television mogul Shonda Rhimes, singer/songwriter Toni Braxton, former WWE wrestler Mick Foley, The View’s Whoopi Goldberg, model Gigi Hadid, and a slew of other elites whose opinions are utterly meaningless. Perhaps the activist media outlet thinks that these high-profile individuals leaving the platform might inspire others to do the same.

The Los Angeles Times published a piece on Friday titled “Thinking of quitting Twitter? Here’s everything you should know,” in which it attempted to explain why folks should seek greener digital pastures.

Ethan Zuckerman, an associate professor at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst’s school of information and computer sciences and director of the Initiative for Digital Public Infrastructure, told the outlet that Musk’s takeover could “mean more abusive content is likely to get through.”

“People have every reason to be worried about the future of Twitter,” Zuckerman fearmongered. ”It’s probably going to be a much less usable network and potentially a much unhealthier network for people who are vulnerable and at risk.”

However, the author of the article admits that “Twitter has no perfect substitute,” and that “it may not make sense for you to jump ship if you’ve built a valuable community on the platform.”

And to what platform are these disgruntled leftists going to flee? So far, it looks like it’s Mastodon, another microblogging platform. However, there appear to be some issues with the site that might make it difficult for progressive Twitter refugees.

The platform, whose founder claims it has over 1 million active users, is plagued with problems making it difficult for people to build a presence.

“For starters, some said they’ve struggled to create an account. The confusion about how to get on the platform has even inspired some to post memes to Twitter,” according to NBC News.

Rob Schäfer, a military historian, told the outlet he threw up his hands and gave up on the site after only 15 minutes of trying to figure it out.

“I write all day, I do a large amount of research and so on; I can’t spend hours learning to handle a simple social media app,” he said Schäfer, who found it to be “clunky” and “unusable.”

German Palestinian filmmaker and activist Lexi Alexander described the platform as “far more complicated to use than Twitter.”

“I think there is a way to have your posts be seen by everybody, as well as see all the posts from everybody on Mastodon,” she said. “But if nobody understands how to do that … it doesn’t really matter.”

“For all activists, it’s the exposure that matters,” the activist continued. “We are trying to make people aware of urgent issues, so a restrictive, hard-to-use platform that separates different groups for different interests will never be an optimal platform for activism.”

logging onto Mastodon pic.twitter.com/YemTzILC8l — Jon Christian (@Jon_Christian) November 9, 2022

While the prospects for another left-leaning social media platform might be slim, we can be sure they won’t stop trying.

But have any of their efforts failed to damage Twitter? According to Musk, not so much:

Twitter user numbers have increased significantly around the world since the deal was announced. And these are very early days. As Twitter becomes by far the most reliable source of truth, it will be indispensable. — Elon Musk (@elonmusk) November 7, 2022

Hit all-time high of active users today — Elon Musk (@elonmusk) November 11, 2022

So far, Twitter is sitting pretty despite the attacks coming from the left. But they are not going to stop here. In fact, as I’ve predicted before, it would not be a surprise to see them try to use the power of the government to stop Musk. Indeed, President Joe Biden already indicated that an investigation could be warranted.

Without any evidence of wrong doing, Biden says Musk is open for investigation. pic.twitter.com/fenxMuzLs0 — Robert Gouveia Esq. (@RobGouveiaEsq) November 12, 2022

The left will stop at nothing to prevent Musk from having his way with Twitter. But the question is: Can they hope to succeed?","[('Elon', 'LOCATION'), ('Musk', 'LOCATION'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('progressive', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Washington', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Now', 'DATE'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Shonda', 'PERSON'), ('Rhimes', 'PERSON'), ('singer', 'TITLE'), ('songwriter', 'TITLE'), ('Toni', 'PERSON'), ('Braxton', 'PERSON'), ('wrestler', 'TITLE'), ('Mick', 'PERSON'), ('Foley', 'PERSON'), ('Whoopi', 'PERSON'), ('Goldberg', 'PERSON'), ('model', 'TITLE'), ('Gigi', 'PERSON'), ('Hadid', 'PERSON'), ('activist', 'TITLE'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Ethan', 'PERSON'), ('Zuckerman', 'PERSON'), ('professor', 'TITLE'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Massachusetts', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Amherst', 'CITY'), ('director', 'TITLE'), ('Initiative', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Digital', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Public', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Infrastructure', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('future', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('author', 'TITLE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('progressive', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('founder', 'TITLE'), ('1', 'NUMBER'), ('million', 'NUMBER'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rob', 'PERSON'), ('Schäfer', 'PERSON'), ('historian', 'TITLE'), ('15', 'DURATION'), ('minutes', 'DURATION'), ('day', 'DURATION'), ('hours', 'DURATION'), ('Schäfer', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NATIONALITY'), ('Palestinian', 'NATIONALITY'), ('filmmaker', 'TITLE'), ('activist', 'TITLE'), ('Lexi', 'PERSON'), ('Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('activist', 'TITLE'), ('Christian', 'RELIGION'), ('@Jon_Christian', 'HANDLE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('9', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('left', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('-', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('leaning', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('early', 'DURATION'), ('days', 'DURATION'), ('@elonmusk', 'HANDLE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('7', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('@elonmusk', 'HANDLE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('11', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('attacks', 'CAUSE_OF_DEATH'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Gouveia', 'PERSON'), ('@RobGouveiaEsq', 'HANDLE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('12', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Twitter', 'ORGANIZATION')]","– Celebrities including Whoopi Goldberg, Shonda Rhimes, and Mick Foley are among those threatening to leave Twitter after Elon Musk's acquisition of the company, the Los Angeles Times reports. ""Twitter has no perfect substitute,"" says Ethan Zuckerman, an associate professor at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst and director of the Initiative for Digital Public Infrastructure. ""It's probably going to be a much less usable network and potentially a much unhealthier network for people who are vulnerable and at risk."" But he adds that ""it may not make sense for you to jump ship if you've built a valuable community on the platform."" Zuckerman tells NBC News that people have ""every reason to be worried"" about the future of Twitter. ""It's probably going to be a much less usable network and potentially a much unhealthier network for people who are vulnerable and at risk,"" he says. And so far, it looks like people on the left are trying to do just that. ""I write all day, I do a large amount of research and so on; I can't spend hours learning to handle a simple social media app,"" military historian Rob Schfer tells NBC. Others say they've struggled to create an account on Mastodon"
8,https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/elon-musks-twitter-deal-is-different-than-most-lbos-heres-how/2022/11/12/7c671b64-62b9-11ed-a131-e900e4a6336b_story.html,FAILED,[],"– Twitter's board has given Elon Musk the green light to move forward with his plan to take the company private, the New York Times reports. In a letter to Twitter's board, Musk says he has ""full confidence"" in the board's approval of the deal, which he says is in the best interest of Twitter's shareholders. The deal is expected to close by the end of the year. Here's what you need to know about Musk's plan to take Twitter private: It's different: This is a leveraged buyout, meaning the buyer doesn't borrow the money to buy the company, Bloomberg explains. Instead, the buyer plays the role of the private equity firm. Musk is providing $33.5 billion in equity, or 72% of the total $46.5 billion in financing. That includes $5.2 billion from 18 equity partners, $1.9 billion from Saudi Prince Alwaleed binal Al Saud, and another $7.1 billion from investors including Larry Ellison. Where's the equity? Most of the equity is coming from Musk, who could sell assets, including more Tesla shares, to fund his equity commitment. What's the debt financing: It's a big headache for the banks, which are on the hook for $13 billion of"
9,https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnbbrandon/2022/11/12/is-social-media-finally-ready-to-evolve/?sh=c262aa6e7146,FAILED,[],"– ""Facebook and Twitter are now the old giants,"" writes Farhad Manjoo in the New York Times. ""Get ready for the new giants. Are you ready?"" Facebook and Twitter had a good run, Manjoo writes, ""catalyzed on the whiteboards of Twitter back in the early days, the entire concept of the early social media firms hinged on massive social connection. Lately, what started as a mere thunderstorm is now a massive conflagration."" We're a little ""bored"" on Facebook and Twitter, and ""digital transmissions emanate into and out of every corner of our lives, by email and text, on apps like SnapChat and emerging apps like BeReal."" ""Can we please not hear about celebrities so often?"" Manjoo writes. ""Social media noise has taken over our lives. What this might mean, finally—after all of this time—is that the powerhouses of social media have simply lost their stronghold (or perhaps, stranglehold)."" Facebook and Twitter ""are now the old giants. Get ready for the new giants. Are you ready?"""
10,https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/democrats-projected-to-keep-control-of-the-senate/ar-AA142INM,"Democrats are projected to keep their majority in the Senate, ABC News reports.

Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto's projected victory in Nevada on Saturday clinched the chamber for Democrats, giving them the 50 seats needed regardless of the outcome of next month's runoff election in Georgia.

The win is a major boost to President Joe Biden in the second half of his term, both for his legislative agenda and his ability to appoint judges and other officials.

Despite having the slimmest of possible Senate majorities -- 50 caucus members and Vice President Kamala Harris as the tie-breaking vote -- Democrats in Biden's first two years were able to pass some of their key priorities.

They gained enough bipartisan support to pass a sweeping infrastructure investment bill, the first major gun safety legislation in decades and legislation boosting domestic production of computer chips.

The party also checked off priority items in reconciliation bills -- legislation that only requires a simple majority for approval. That's how Democrats passed the American Rescue Plan, which provided COVID-19 funds, and the Inflation Reduction Act, which made investments in climate change and health care.

Control of the House was still up in the air on Saturday, as vote counting continued in more than a dozen races. How much Biden will be able to accomplish will also hinge on whether Republicans or Democrats control the lower chamber. Republicans have already laid the groundwork for investigations of the Biden administration and even members of the president's family.

© Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer speaks during a news conference following the weekly Caucus Meeting with Senate Democrats at the Capitol, Aug. 2, 2022.

Still, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer, D-N.Y., took a moment late Saturday to celebrate the Senate win.

""This election is a victory -- a victory and a vindication for Democrats, our agenda, and for America and for the American people,"" Schumer said as he held a press conference at his Manhattan office.

""The American people rejected -- soundly rejected -- the anti-democratic, authoritarian, nasty, and divisive direction that MAGA Republicans wanted to take our country in,"" he added.

The fate of the Senate came down to just a handful of battleground states, including Arizona and Pennsylvania. Political heavyweights for the party, including Biden and former President Barack Obama, hit the campaign trail hard in the final weeks in an attempt to stoke enthusiasm.

Republicans gained ground with voters in those races in the final stretch of the campaigns, polling showed, but Democrats emerged victorious.

Democratic Sen. Mark Kelly defeated Republican Blake Masters in Arizona. Pennsylvania's race was projected on election night for Democrat John Fetterman, who won against celebrity Dr. Mehmet Oz and flipped the seat opened by retiring Republican Sen. Pat Toomey.

Georgia's Senate race between Democratic incumbent Raphael Warnock and Republican Herschel Walker is heading to a runoff on Dec. 6. Neither candidate received more than 50% of the vote, but Warnock led Walker 49-48%.

Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell, R-Ky., earlier this year tempered expectations of a red wave by questioning ""candidate quality."" While he didn't name any candidates, among the more controversial Republican nominees this cycle were Walker in Georgia or Oz in Pennsylvania.

""I think there's probably a greater likelihood the House flips than the Senate. Senate races are just different,"" the GOP leader said. ""Candidate quality has a lot to do with the outcome.""

Still, McConnell's Senate Leadership Fund spent at least $230 million this cycle trying to win back control of the chamber, according to OpenSecrets.

The Senate Majority PAC, a group aligned with Schumer, spent at least $155 million, according to OpenSecrets.","[('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('ABC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Catherine', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('50', 'NUMBER'), ('next', 'DATE'), ('month', 'DATE'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('50', 'NUMBER'), ('Vice', 'TITLE'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Kamala', 'PERSON'), ('Harris', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'DURATION'), ('years', 'DURATION'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('decades', 'DURATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('American', 'NATIONALITY'), ('Rescue', 'MISC'), ('Plan', 'MISC'), ('COVID', 'MISC'), ('-', 'MISC'), ('19', 'MISC'), ('Inflation', 'MISC'), ('Reduction', 'MISC'), ('Act', 'MISC'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('dozen', 'NUMBER'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('Anna', 'PERSON'), ('Moneymaker', 'PERSON'), ('Getty', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Images', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leader', 'TITLE'), ('Chuck', 'PERSON'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('weekly', 'SET'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Capitol', 'LOCATION'), ('Aug.', 'DATE'), ('2', 'DATE'), (',', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leader', 'TITLE'), ('Chuck', 'PERSON'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('D', 'LOCATION'), ('-', 'LOCATION'), ('N.Y.', 'LOCATION'), ('late', 'DATE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('America', 'COUNTRY'), ('American', 'NATIONALITY'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('Manhattan', 'CITY'), ('American', 'NATIONALITY'), ('MAGA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Arizona', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Pennsylvania', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Barack', 'PERSON'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DURATION'), ('final', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Kelly', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Blake', 'PERSON'), ('Arizona', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Pennsylvania', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('night', 'TIME'), ('Democrat', 'MISC'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Fetterman', 'PERSON'), ('Mehmet', 'PERSON'), ('Oz', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Pat', 'PERSON'), ('Toomey', 'PERSON'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Raphael', 'PERSON'), ('Warnock', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Herschel', 'PERSON'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Dec.', 'DATE'), ('6', 'DATE'), ('candidate', 'TITLE'), ('50', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Warnock', 'PERSON'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'PERCENT'), ('-', 'PERCENT'), ('48', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Minority', 'TITLE'), ('Leader', 'TITLE'), ('Mitch', 'PERSON'), ('McConnell', 'PERSON'), ('R', 'LOCATION'), ('-', 'LOCATION'), ('Ky.', 'LOCATION'), ('earlier', 'DATE'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('candidate', 'TITLE'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Pennsylvania', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('leader', 'TITLE'), ('Candidate', 'TITLE'), ('McConnell', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('230', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Majority', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('PAC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('155', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY')]","– The good news for Democrats is that they will keep their majority in the Senate, reports ABC News. The bad news is that they won't be able to confirm many of President Trump's nominees. The good news is that Joe Biden will be able to appoint more judges. The bad news is that Republicans will still control the House. Here's a look at some of the key races still up in the air: Arizona: Democratic Sen. Mark Kelly defeated Republican Blake Masters. Pennsylvania: Democratic Sen. John Fetterman defeated celebrity Dr. Mehmet Oz. Georgia: Republican Herschel Walker will face Democrat Raphael Warnock in a runoff election Dec. 6."
11,https://www.newsweek.com/what-keeping-senate-means-joe-bidens-presidency-1759142,FAILED,[],"The good news for Democrats is that they'll be in control of the Senate for at least two more years. The bad news is that they still don't have the 60 votes needed to pass many of President Trump's agenda items. The good news is that they'll be able to confirm many of the president's nominees to federal judgeships without Republican support, reports Newsweek. Nevada Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto was re-elected to a second term on Saturday, giving Democrats the 50 seats they need to control the upper chamber. Vice President Kamala Harris was able to cast the tie-breaking vote. Democrats could still win another, however, if Georgia Senator Raphael Warnock is able to retain his seat in a December 6 runoff against his Republican challenger, Herschel Walker."
12,https://www.cbsnews.com/live-updates/elections-2022-results-democrats-clinch-senate-control/,"Dog sniffs out 2,000 fentanyl pills baked into bread rolls

Senate set to hold crucial vote on advancing marriage equality bill

Boy, woman stabbed with butcher knife at LA Target store; suspect killed

""Completely dehydrated"" girl among migrants bussed from Texas to Philly

Trump announces he's running for president again in 2024

NASA launches Artemis rocket on a mission to the moon

NATO: ""No indication"" Russia attacked Poland after blast near Ukraine

Kathryn Watson is a politics reporter for CBS News Digital based in Washington, D.C.

Catherine Cortez Masto projected to defeat Adam Laxalt and win reelection

Catherine Cortez Masto projected to defeat Adam Laxalt and win reelection

Georgia Democrats sue to open up early voting on Saturday of Thanksgiving weekend

Georgia Democrats sue to open up early voting on Saturday of Thanksgiving weekend

2022 midterm elections: Election deniers who won and lost

2022 midterm elections: Election deniers who won and lost

Democrats retain control of Senate with House still up for grabs

House control still up for grabs

House control still up for grabs

Be the first to know

Get browser notifications for breaking news, live events, and exclusive reporting.

Not Now

Turn On","[('2,000', 'NUMBER'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('butcher', 'TITLE'), ('LA', 'CITY'), ('Texas', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Philly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trump', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('NASA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('NATO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Russia', 'COUNTRY'), ('Poland', 'COUNTRY'), ('Ukraine', 'COUNTRY'), ('Kathryn', 'PERSON'), ('Watson', 'PERSON'), ('reporter', 'TITLE'), ('CBS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Digital', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Washington', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('D.C.', 'LOCATION'), ('Catherine', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('Catherine', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('Georgia', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Thanksgiving', 'DATE'), ('weekend', 'DATE'), ('Georgia', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Thanksgiving', 'DATE'), ('weekend', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Now', 'DATE')]","– President Trump's former personal lawyer and ""fixer"" Michael Cohen is going to plead guilty to tax evasion, bank fraud, and campaign finance violations before a federal judge in New York on Tuesday, the AP reports. Cohen, who has been acting as Trump's personal lawyer since last year, will face a maximum of 20 years in prison and a $250,000 fine if he's found to have violated campaign finance laws. Cohen will also be required to testify before a grand jury, according to the New York Daily News. The guilty plea is the first time Cohen has pleaded guilty to a federal felony since the special counsel's office opened an investigation into Trump's campaign ahead of the 2016 election. Cohen, who is cooperating with the special counsel's office, will also face a maximum of 10 years in prison and a $250,000 fine if he's found to have violated campaign finance laws."
13,https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2022/11/12/catherine-cortez-masto-defeats-laxalt-nevada/10680683002/,"Ella Lee and Emilee Miranda

Democrats will retain control of the U.S. Senate after incumbent Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto, D-Nev., prevailed in a nail-biting race against Republican challenger Adam Laxalt.

The nation's first Latina senator, Cortez Masto was widely regarded as the Senate's most vulnerable incumbent Democrat, with national Republicans identifying her seat as the party's best chance to flip.

But with her seat secured, Democrats are guaranteed control of Congress' upper chamber no matter the outcome of a run-off race in Georgia between incumbent Democratic Sen. Raphael Warnock and Republican challenger Herschel Walker, thanks to Vice President Kamala Harris' tie-breaking vote.

Live election updates:Democrats will keep Senate after Cortez Masto defeats Laxalt in Nevada

OnPolitics newsletter:Fast and to the point, delivered to your inbox

Democrats poured resources into Nevada's Senate race at the 11th hour, including by sending one of their most persuasive surrogates, former President Barack Obama, to campaign there. In Nevada, Obama delivered the same key message he shared in other battleground states in the weeks before the election: ""Democracy is on the ballot.""

A former one-term state attorney general, Laxalt focused his campaign on inflation and the economy, placing the blame on Cortez Masto and President Joe Biden. Cortez Masto made reproductive health care central to her bid for a second term after the Supreme Court reversed Roe v. Wade this summer.

Nevada Senate race:Nevada's 2022 Senate race tests potency of abortion focus for Cortez Masto, Democrats

2022 Election Results:Follow key races in the 2022 midterm elections as they are decided

Money matters

With control of the Senate at stake, the race attracted huge amounts of cash.

Cortez Masto had raised $58.5 million and spent $48.3 million by mid-October, according to her latest report with the Federal Election Commission. Laxalt reported $15.8 million and spending $12.6 million in the same period.

But the campaigns' fundraising was overshadowed by $126.5 million in outside spending, according to OpenSecrets.org, with much of that total coming in the form of opposition to one candidate or the other.","[('Ella', 'PERSON'), ('Lee', 'PERSON'), ('Emilee', 'PERSON'), ('Miranda', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Catherine', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('D', 'LOCATION'), ('-', 'LOCATION'), ('Nev.', 'LOCATION'), ('Republican', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latina', 'CITY'), ('senator', 'TITLE'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrat', 'MISC'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Raphael', 'PERSON'), ('Warnock', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Herschel', 'PERSON'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Vice', 'TITLE'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Kamala', 'PERSON'), ('Harris', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('the', 'DATE'), ('11th', 'DATE'), ('hour', 'DATE'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Barack', 'PERSON'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('the', 'DURATION'), ('weeks', 'DURATION'), ('Democracy', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('-', 'NUMBER'), ('term', 'NUMBER'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('a', 'DURATION'), ('second', 'DURATION'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roe', 'PERSON'), ('this', 'DATE'), ('summer', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('2022', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('58.5', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('48.3', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Election', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Laxalt', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('15.8', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('12.6', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('$', 'MONEY'), ('126.5', 'MONEY'), ('million', 'MONEY'), ('OpenSecrets.org', 'URL'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('candidate', 'TITLE')]","– It was a nail-biter, but Democrats will keep control of the Senate. Nevada incumbent Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto defeated Republican challenger Adam Laxalt on Tuesday night, the AP reports. Cortez Masto, the first Latina elected to the Senate, had been widely seen as the most vulnerable Democratic incumbent and the party's best chance to flip the seat. Laxalt, the state's Republican attorney general, had been seen as the party's best chance to flip the seat. But with her seat secured, Democrats are guaranteed control of Congress' upper chamber no matter the outcome of a run-off race in Georgia between incumbent Democratic Sen. Raphael Warnock and Republican challenger Herschel Walker, thanks to Vice President Kamala Harris' tie-breaking vote. Live election results: Cortez Masto defeated Laxalt in Nevada's Senate race at the 11th hour, including by sending one of their most persuasive surrogates, former President Obama. In Nevada, Obama delivered the same key message he shared in other battleground states in the weeks before the election: ""Democracy is on the ballot."" A former one-term state attorney general, Laxalt focused his campaign on inflation and the economy, placing the blame on Cortez Masto and President Joe Biden."
14,https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2022-11-12/2022-midterm-election-democrats-keep-control-of-senate-after-cortez-masto-win-in-nevada,"Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto, a Nevada Democrat, ensured her party will keep control of the Senate after she defeated Republican Adam Laxalt, the state’s former attorney general.

The race was called Saturday by the Associated Press. Meanwhile, control of the U.S. House of Representatives remains too close to call, underscoring how Democrats continue to outperform expectations and deny the GOP’s hopes for a sizable majority.

A jubilant Senate Majority Leader Charles E. Schumer (D-N.Y.) said the results were “a victory and a vindication” for his party, speaking Saturday evening at a hastily convened news conference in New York. He credited the quality of Democratic candidates as well as the party’s legislative agenda and an electorate willing to reject “the antidemocratic, extremist MAGA Republicans.”

“Contrast our candidates with some of the people they ran against. Our strong candidates beat some very flawed challengers who had no faith in democracy, no fidelity in truth or honor, and even when the polls looked bleak, our candidates never gave up and never lost faith,” Schumer said. “As the MAGA Republicans stoked fear and division, Democrats were talking about how we delivered on issues that matter to people.”

Advertisement

President Biden, with his party holding the Senate, preserves his ability to confirm judicial nominees and Cabinet secretaries.

The president received news of Democrats’ Senate success while in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, where he is attending the Association of Southeast Asian Nations summit.

“I feel good and I’m looking forward to the next couple of years,” he said. He expressed hope his party would also claim the House, but acknowledged “it’s a stretch where everything has to fall our way.”

Ronald Klain, Biden’s chief of staff, celebrated on Twitter by typing the number of seats Democrats now hold — 50 — and 14 exclamation points.

Prominent Republicans met the news with silence Saturday evening — at least publicly. Neither Senate GOP leader Mitch McConnell nor Sen. Rick Scott of Florida, who leads the GOP Senate campaign arm, released a comment.

Keeping the Senate was considered a slightly easier task for Democrats than retaining control in the House. National dynamics — such as presidential approval ratings and economic concerns — exert less force on statewide races; in 2018, for example, Republicans picked up two Senate seats even as Democrats gained 40 seats to win control of the House.

Still, with high inflation and a dissatisfied electorate, the battle for control of the Senate was a toss-up for much of the cycle. Democrats were boosted by dominant fundraising and voter outrage after the Supreme Court reversed decades-old federal protections for access to abortion — a backlash that Schumer said was crucial to the party’s victories.

“Because the American people turned out to elect Democrats in the Senate, there is now a firewall against the nationwide abortion ban threat that so many Republicans have talked about,” Schumer said.

Democrats also benefited from GOP opponents who were popular with Trump supporters but less so with the general electorate.

Jessica Taylor, a Senate campaign analyst with the nonpartisan Cook Political Report with Amy Walter, said she would never have imagined at the beginning of the cycle that the Democrats could find themselves on the cusp of picking up a Senate seat.

“When we look at history and the current political climate and economic indicators, it is shocking that Democrats may not have lost a single incumbent,” Taylor said.

Democrats will have an opportunity to build on their majority next month in Georgia, when Sen. Raphael Warnock faces off against GOP challenger Herschel Walker. Warnock narrowly outran Walker in Tuesday’s general election. But he failed to surpass 50% of the vote, forcing a runoff under state law.

Walker ran 5 percentage points behind Gov. Brian Kemp, a fellow Republican who made a successful reelection bid — pointing to a significant number of voters who backed the incumbent governor but not Walker.

Now that control of the Senate has been determined, it may be difficult for Walker to rally those voters to show up, Taylor said.

“It’s a turnout game, and Republicans failed the turnout game last time because [then-President] Trump was trying to overturn the election results,” Taylor said, pointing to the GOP’s loss of two Senate runoffs in Georgia after the 2020 election.

In Nevada, the race between Laxalt and Cortez Masto — viewed as the Senate’s most vulnerable Democrat in the lead-up to Tuesday’s midterm election — came down to the slimmest of margins. The contest was so close in part because the state’s voters are closely divided between the two major parties. Democrats had less than a 4-percentage-point registration edge over Republicans as of Nov. 1.

On paper, Nevada looks like a solid-blue state. All but one of its statewide offices are held by Democrats; the party has majorities in both state legislative houses and in its congressional delegation. Democratic presidential candidates have won the state since 2008, when Barack Obama prevailed with a double-digit victory.

But Democrats’ winning streak in Nevada belies the grind-it-out nature of many of their victories. Powered by the vaunted “Reid machine” — the political turnout operation built by the late Senate Democratic leader Harry Reid, the state’s longest-serving senator — Nevada only narrowly tilted in the party’s direction in the 2016 and 2020 presidential races. Cortez Masto won her first term in 2016 by under 3 percentage points.

Democrats have relied on working-class voters of color, especially union members, to bolster their margins in close elections. But the party’s struggles to win over people without college degrees, and a rightward drift among Latino voters, made Nevada especially challenging terrain.

The state’s workforce is transient, and many voters’ livelihoods depend on visitors eating, drinking, gambling and otherwise cavorting on the Las Vegas Strip and its environs — a tourism industry that has yet to fully rebound after being curtailed by the pandemic. The state’s unemployment rate and gas prices remain among the highest in the country.

“We’ve known this was going to be a tough campaign,” said Cortez Masto in a victory speech Sunday. “But like all of you, I’m a Nevadan, and I know what it takes to deliver for my own state. So when the national pundits said I couldn’t win, I knew Nevada would prove them wrong.”

Cortez Masto, 58, a former state attorney general, is the daughter of a four-term Clark County commissioner. She made history in 2016 as the first Latina elected to the Senate.

Laxalt, 44, is a former state attorney general who unsuccessfully ran for governor in 2018. The grandson of a Nevada governor and senator who was a confidant of President Reagan, Laxalt co-chaired Trump’s 2020 campaign in the state. Trump campaigned with him on Nov. 5.

“This is another place where we saw Trump having more of an impact,” Taylor said, noting that Laxalt was part of the legal team that tried to help the former president overturn the 2020 election results.

Trump is poised to loom over the upcoming runoff as well, teasing a possible announcement for a 2024 presidential run next week.

Election denialism was unpopular with voters in Nevada; Jim Marchant, the GOP secretary of state candidate who was among the most vocal purveyors of voting conspiracies, lost to Democrat Cisco Aguilar, the AP reported Saturday evening.

But Republican gubernatorial candidate Joe Lombardo successfully ousted Democratic incumbent Steve Sisolak.

While Lombardo was endorsed by Trump and appeared with him at rallies, he also tried to distance himself from the former president at times, describing him as a “sound president” in a debate after declining to call Trump “great.”

Lombardo’s position as the sheriff of Clark County, the state’s population hub, also enabled him to run a campaign more focused on crime, a theme that Republican candidates across the country emphasized.

Times staff writers Nolan D. McCaskill in Washington and Hannah Fry in Los Angeles contributed to this report.","[('Catherine', 'PERSON'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Democrat', 'MISC'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Adam', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Associated', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Representatives', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Leader', 'TITLE'), ('Charles', 'PERSON'), ('E.', 'PERSON'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('evening', 'TIME'), ('New', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('York', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('MAGA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Republicans', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('democracy', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('MAGA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cabinet', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Phnom', 'LOCATION'), ('Penh', 'LOCATION'), ('Cambodia', 'COUNTRY'), ('Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Southeast', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Asian', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Nations', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('the', 'DURATION'), ('next', 'DURATION'), ('couple', 'DURATION'), ('of', 'DURATION'), ('years', 'DURATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ronald', 'PERSON'), ('Klain', 'PERSON'), ('Biden', 'PERSON'), ('chief', 'TITLE'), ('of', 'TITLE'), ('staff', 'TITLE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('50', 'NUMBER'), ('14', 'NUMBER'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('evening', 'TIME'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('leader', 'TITLE'), ('Mitch', 'PERSON'), ('McConnell', 'PERSON'), ('Rick', 'PERSON'), ('Scott', 'PERSON'), ('Florida', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('two', 'NUMBER'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('40', 'NUMBER'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('American', 'NATIONALITY'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('now', 'DATE'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Schumer', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('Jessica', 'PERSON'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('analyst', 'TITLE'), ('nonpartisan', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Cook', 'TITLE'), ('Amy', 'PERSON'), ('Walter', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('current', 'DATE'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('next', 'DATE'), ('month', 'DATE'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Raphael', 'PERSON'), ('Warnock', 'PERSON'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Herschel', 'PERSON'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Warnock', 'PERSON'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('50', 'PERCENT'), ('%', 'PERCENT'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('5', 'NUMBER'), ('Gov.', 'TITLE'), ('Brian', 'PERSON'), ('Kemp', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('governor', 'TITLE'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Now', 'DATE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Walker', 'PERSON'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), (']', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('two', 'NUMBER'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Georgia', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Laxalt', 'LOCATION'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democrat', 'MISC'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('two', 'NUMBER'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('4', 'NUMBER'), ('-', 'NUMBER'), ('percentage', 'NUMBER'), ('-', 'NUMBER'), ('point', 'NUMBER'), ('Republicans', 'MISC'), ('Nov.', 'DATE'), ('1', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('one', 'NUMBER'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('Barack', 'PERSON'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('leader', 'TITLE'), ('Harry', 'PERSON'), ('Reid', 'PERSON'), ('senator', 'TITLE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('3', 'NUMBER'), ('Democrats', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Latino', 'MISC'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Las', 'CITY'), ('Vegas', 'CITY'), ('Strip', 'LOCATION'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Cortez', 'PERSON'), ('Masto', 'PERSON'), ('58', 'NUMBER'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('four', 'NUMBER'), ('-', 'NUMBER'), ('term', 'NUMBER'), ('Clark', 'CITY'), ('County', 'TITLE'), ('commissioner', 'TITLE'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Latina', 'CITY'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('44', 'NUMBER'), ('attorney', 'TITLE'), ('general', 'TITLE'), ('governor', 'TITLE'), ('2018', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('governor', 'TITLE'), ('senator', 'TITLE'), ('President', 'TITLE'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Nov.', 'DATE'), ('5', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Taylor', 'PERSON'), ('Laxalt', 'PERSON'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('2020', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('2024', 'DATE'), ('next', 'DATE'), ('week', 'DATE'), ('Nevada', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Jim', 'PERSON'), ('Marchant', 'PERSON'), ('GOP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('secretary', 'TITLE'), ('of', 'TITLE'), ('state', 'TITLE'), ('candidate', 'TITLE'), ('Democrat', 'MISC'), ('Cisco', 'PERSON'), ('Aguilar', 'PERSON'), ('AP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('evening', 'TIME'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('gubernatorial', 'TITLE'), ('candidate', 'TITLE'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Lombardo', 'PERSON'), ('Democratic', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Steve', 'PERSON'), ('Sisolak', 'PERSON'), ('Lombardo', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('president', 'TITLE'), ('Lombardo', 'PERSON'), ('sheriff', 'TITLE'), ('Clark', 'CITY'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('Republican', 'IDEOLOGY'), ('Nolan', 'PERSON'), ('D.', 'PERSON'), ('McCaskill', 'PERSON'), ('Washington', 'STATE_OR_PROVINCE'), ('Hannah', 'PERSON'), ('Fry', 'PERSON'), ('Los', 'CITY'), ('Angeles', 'CITY')]","– Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer called it ""a victory and a vindication"" Saturday night for Democrats, who will keep control of the Senate for at least the next two years. ""Our strong candidates beat some very flawed challengers who had no faith in democracy, no fidelity in truth or honor, and even when the polls looked bleak, our candidates never gave up and never lost faith,"" Schumer said at a news conference in New York, per the Los Angeles Times. ""As the MAGA Republicans stoked fear and division, Democrats were talking about how we delivered on issues that matter to people."" The AP called the race in Nevada for Democratic Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto, who defeated Republican Adam Laxalt, the state's former attorney general. In another closely watched race, Georgia incumbent Sen. Raphael Warnock defeated GOP challenger Herschel Walker to keep the seat in Democratic hands, the Atlanta Journal-Constitution reports. In other races:"
15,https://www.foxnews.com/politics/democrats-maintain-control-united-states-senate,"Democrats will have continued control of the Senate, the Fox News Decision Desk can project.

Democrats will maintain power in the Senate thanks to Democratic Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto being declared the winner in Nevada on Saturday night in her race against Republican challenger Adam Laxalt.

Democrats now hold 50 seats compared to the 49 seats held by Republicans with one seat yet to be decided in Georgia where a runoff election will be held between Republican Herschel Walker and Democratic Sen. Raphael Warnock on December 6th.

Even if Walker were to win in Georgia, Democrats would still have control with Vice President Kamala Harris's tie-breaking vote.

MIDTERM ELECTIONS 2022: LIVE UPDATES

""Voters across the country have delivered a resounding endorsement of Democrats’ Senate majority,"" Democratic Senatorial Campaign Committee Chair Sen. Gary Peters said in a statement. ""These historic results in race after race speak for themselves, and they reflect the strength of our candidates, the popularity of Senate Democrats' message to the American people, and a rejection of the extremism espoused by the GOP. Now our work continues in Georgia to ensure Herschel Walker is defeated and Rev. Warnock is re-elected.""

Prior to Tuesday's nationwide midterm elections, Democrats held a razor-thin majority in the upper chamber of Congress with 50 seats in their party's control. Because Vice President Kamala Harris has the ability to cast tie-breaking votes, Democrats only needed 50 seats to keep control.

Prior to 2021, the last time Democrats controlled the Senate was from January 2013 to January 2015 during the 113th Congress.

In this year's midterm elections, Republicans were forced to defend 21 seats, while Democrats had to defend just 14. Three of the four closest Senate races this cycle featured a Democrat incumbent.
